翻译   草草
时间轴   兜兜兜爹
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
鸣谢   忙成狗的网飞
鸣谢   阿小小海
特效   草草
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第三季  第七集
你是否愿意再次确认
Do you renew your commitment
与这名女子结为合法夫妇的承诺
to this woman as your lawful wedded wife,
爱她  尊敬她  照顾她
to love her, honor her, comfort her,
无论罹病或安康
keep her in sickness and in health,
心无二意  忠于她
forsaking all others, be true to her,
直到生命尽头
as long as you both shall live?
我愿意
I do.
你是否愿意再次确认
Do you renew your commitment to this man
与这名男子结为合法夫妇的承诺
as your lawful wedded husband,
爱他  尊敬他  照顾他
to love him, honor him, comfort him,
无论罹病或安康
keep him in sickness and in health,
心无二意  忠于他
forsaking all others, be true to him,
直到生命尽头
as long as you both shall live?
我愿意
I do.
愿这再次确认的承诺  能加深你们的爱情
May this renewed commitment deepen your love for each other
让你们的婚姻更加坚固  直到永远
and strengthen your eternal bond.
弗兰西斯
Francis?
把尸体抬下去时不要拍照
No photographs when they unload his body.
能答应我吗
Will you promise me that?
第一夫人反抗佩特罗夫
很多人说你是英雄呢
A lot of people are calling you a hero.
也有很多人不那么看
A lot of people aren't.
弗兰西斯  我会让维和决议案
Francis, I will get this peacekeeping resolution
在联合国大会上通过的
passed through the General Assembly.
这是我欠你的
I owe you that.
我们明天要为总统像拍照
So we have the photograph tomorrow for the presidential portrait.
他们要靠这个画像
It's what they're gonna base the painting on.
我要笑  你呢
I'll be smiling. Will you?
他们干什么呢
What are they doing?
是文化交流  跟西藏
Part of a... cultural exchange, sir, with Tibet.
他们会待一个月
They'll be here for a month.
一个月
A month?
别担心  你的字是鬼画符
Don't worry, your handwriting's atrocious.
什么都看不懂
Couldn't read a thing.
-汤姆  -我知道  凯特·鲍德温
- Tom. - I know. Kate Baldwin.
我知道
I know.
我们真不错
Gold stars for us.
两个月
It only took two months
同乘一架飞机  总算互相介绍了
riding on the same plane to introduce ourselves.
或许我就是害羞呢
Maybe I'm shy.
才不是  你就是不屑于跟平头百姓打交道
Oh, no, you're not. You just don't mingle with the peasants.
要说我们谁是平头百姓  那也是我
If one of us is a peasant, I think it's me.
抱歉我不能留在加夫尼陪你
I'm sorry I can't stay here in Gaffney with you.
没事
It's okay.
我们明天见
I'll see you tomorrow.
或许今晚就能见  如果顺利
Maybe tonight, if all goes well.
觉得乐观吗
Feeling optimistic?
我给了你一个承诺
I made you a promise.
走吧  飞机等着你呢
Well, go on. You have a plane waiting.
谢谢
Thank you.
汤姆
Tom.
共和党要引入一份
The Republicans are introducing a bill
《斯塔福德法案》的修正案
that amends the Stafford Act.
他们说用联邦应急管理署的资金
They say that the siphoning of FEMA funds
来资助《美国就业法案》有违拨款法规
for America Works violates the appropriation.
让他们去吧
So let them.
两党都会支持
It's got bipartisan support.
邓巴会公开支持修正案
Dunbar's going to publicly support the bill.
-杰姬呢  -她不想搅进去
- What about Jackie? - She's trying to stay out of it,
但如果投票了  她只能随大流
but if it goes to a vote, she's gotta go with the tide.
她的民调数字
We don't want her poll numbers
刚刚开始追上邓巴  不能这时受挫
to take a hit as she's starting to gain on Dunbar.
如果他们通过修正案  我就否决
If they pass the bill, I'll veto it.
他们推翻  我就拒绝执行
If they override, I'll refuse to enforce.
等闹到最高法院
By the time it gets to the Supreme Court,
我们已经可以拿出就业成果了
we'll have jobs to show,
他们只能耍嘴皮子
they'll have nothing but rhetoric.
这是公关战  与法律无关
This is a public relations battle, not a legal one.
发声明吗
Statement?
就我说的  火药味儿轻点
Just what I just said, less combative.
我们怎么拍
So, how do we want to do this?
我认为第一夫人应该坐着  您站在她身后
I think the First Lady should sit. You behind her.
这样可以吗  安德伍德夫人
Does that work for you, Mrs. Underwood?
当然  效果好就行
Uh, yes, whatever works best.
我先为夫人调灯光  然后给您找位置  先生
Let me adjust the light for her, and then I'll place you, sir.
非洲集团给
The African bloc just added
维和决议案加了一项条款
a provision to the peacekeeping resolution.
什么内容
What does it say?
要求非洲指挥维和军队
Requires African command of the forces.
这是故意坏事  弗兰西斯
It's a poison pill, Francis.
以色列和巴勒斯坦都不可能同意
There's no way Israel or Palestine will get on board with that.
你觉得是俄罗斯在指使吗
You think the Russians are behind it?
可能吧  凯茜和我还在调查
Probably. Cathy and I are investigating.
好了  总统先生  请站在您妻子身后
All right, Mr. President. Just behind your wife, please.
不要我放吗
Do you prefer I not?
什么
What?
您放手的位置很好
Where you had your hand is perfect.
很好  好了  拍了
Great. All right. Here we go.
请再笑一点
A little more of a smile, please.
请进
Come in.
今天有进展吗
Any luck today?
莫里科夫  说不是他们
Moryakov... says it wasn't them.
我倒不怎么相信他
Not that I trust him.
现在我只能设法让津巴布韦开口了
So now I just need to see if I can get Zimbabwe to talk.
今天  我们拍照的时候
Today, when we took the photo...
我碰了你的肩
I touched your shoulder.
怎么了
Yes?
你躲了一下
You flinched.
-什么  -我感觉到了
- What? - I felt it.
没有啊
No, I didn't.
就好像...
It was like...
你缩了一下
you recoiled.
我觉得你是想多了
I think you're reading too much into something
而且我觉得根本没这回事
that I don't think actually happened.
好吧  当我没说过
All right. Forget I said anything.
等等
Wait.
我就是...
I just...
算了  我也不知道我是想说什么
Never mind. I don't know what I was gonna say.
晚安
Good night.
房子应该就在那边
House must've been somewhere out there.
如果能算得上是房子
Well, if you can call it a house.
不比那辆卡车大多少
It was no bigger than that truck.
农场完全拆了  这倒也好
Nothing left of the farm, which is for the best.
桃树在这里都不结果
Peaches didn't want to grow here anyway.
在表土下两英尺就是石头的地上
That's what you get for planting on land
种东西  还能有什么好结果
with solid rock two feet below the topsoil.
这事我们应该
You know, that's one of the points
在书里提及
that we should make in the book,
在合适的环境里辛勤劳作才能有结果
that hard work is only worth it in the right conditions.
我们想帮助大家成功
We want to set people up for success.
职业培训  合理的职业道路
Vocational training, legitimate career paths.
欢迎回来  加夫尼怎么样
Welcome back. How was Gaffney?
我们跟卡斯皮大使安排时间了吗
Do we have a time set for Ambassador Caspi yet?
她办公室那边在拖
Her office is stalling.
跟她约好  她在哪方便见面都行
Get her schedule. We'll go wherever she is.
她应该会参加今晚的鸡尾酒会
I think she'll be at the cocktail reception tonight
-在墨西哥领事馆  -我去打电话确认
- at the Mexican Consulate. - I'll call and find out.
那是什么
What's that?
今早寄来给你的
It came in for you this morning.
弗兰西斯吗
Francis?
约翰·帕斯特纳克  迈克尔·科里根的丈夫
John Pasternak. Michael Corrigan's husband.
最新的采访请求放在你桌上了
The latest pile of interview requests is on your desk,
大都跟科里根事件有关
most of them Corrigan related.
反歧视同性恋联盟希望你去他们的
And GLAAD wants you to be a keynote speaker
媒体颁奖典礼做主讲人
at their Media Awards Ceremony.
他怎么知道的
How did he know?
你婚誓重证的事吗  新闻上有
About your vows? It's been in the news.
不是  我喜欢郁金香的事
No, that I liked tulips.
恭喜婚誓重证
爱情恒久远
约·帕
你母亲工作吗
Did your mother work?
主要是做女仆
As a maid, mostly.
她挺受欢迎  因为她是白人
In high demand, because she was white.
大家认定她不会偷贵重东西
People assumed she wouldn't steal any valuables,
但她当然还是偷了
but of course she did.
我记得有一晚  她回家时拿着两枚蓝宝石耳环
I remember one night, she came home with two sapphire earrings.
第二天她拿去了斯帕坦堡的当铺
She took them to the pawn shop in Spartanburg the next day,
但前一晚她戴了一整晚  睡觉也没摘
but she wore them all night long, even slept in them.
她大概是想知道
I guess she wanted to know
戴真珠宝是什么感觉
what it felt like to have real jewelry,
哪怕只是几小时
even if it was just for a few hours.
这可别写进书里
That does not go in the book.
你父母怎么不多生几个孩子
Why didn't your parents have any more kids?
这跟我们的话题无关
That's not relevant to what we're doing.
我只是想了解你的家庭
I'm just trying to get a sense of your family.
谷仓应该就在那边
The barn must've been somewhere right over there.
我父亲以前会躲进谷仓避开我们
My father used to escape in there to get away from us.
一般还带一瓶酒进去
Usually brought a bottle with him.
你爱你父亲吗
Did you love your father?
他内心深处是个好人
He was a good man, down deep.
他十分爱我们
He cared for us greatly.
努力工作  供养家庭
Worked hard to put food on the table.
并不能总能做到  但并非他不努力
Didn't always succeed, but that wasn't for a lack of trying.
瞧  这不是回答
See... that's not an answer.
我问你你是否爱你父亲  你却不说
I asked you if you loved your father, you don't tell me.
你只说你希望我写的东西
You tell me what you want me to write.
你从一开始就是这样
Which is what you've done since the beginning.
你该开始说实话了
It's time to start telling the truth.
-你觉得我一直在撒谎吗  -我确定
- You think I've been lying? - I know you have.
你唯一没撒谎的一次  是在白宫那一晚
The only time you haven't is that one night in the White House.
我经历的最糟的一次历险  我告诉你们
The worst adventure I've ever been on. I can promise you...
-我不明白  -这游戏赢不了
- I don't get it. - The game is unwinnable.
-那有什么意义  -意义就在这里
- What is the point? - That is the point.
我认为我们
I find it unlikely that
如果反复重新开始  是不可能进步的
we'll ever progress by starting over and over again.
-但总得比这强  -天呐
- But it's got to be better than this. - Oh, God.
我们试试吧  何不呢
Okay, let's give it a shot. Why not?
-有件事很明确  -又重启了
- Something was very clear. - It just started over again.
总是一遍遍重启
It keeps doing that over and over.
你无视他的指示  他就让你从头开始
Ignore his instructions, he sends you back.
如果我遵照指示呢
What if I follow his instructions?
混乱一片  完全随机
Chaos takes over. Randomness.
根本无法遵从规则
It's impossible to follow the rules.
下次吧  这太接近我的现实生活了
Another time. It's too much like my real life.
再说  我们不该玩游戏
Besides, we shouldn't be playing games.
你应该向我提问
You should be asking me questions.
你要把我灌醉了
You're getting me drunk.
我肯定要记不住我问了什么了
I won't remember what I asked.
我上次喝得这么醉  我闯进了一座图书馆
The last time I got this drunk, I broke into a library.
在查尔斯顿  我母校
In Charleston, my alma mater.
桑蒂诺
The Sentinel.
我差点吐在自己身上
I almost puked all over myself.
第八章  《总统大吐》
That's Chapter Eight: "POTUS Blows Chunks."
能小点声吗
Can you keep it down, please?
-一起来嘛  -抱歉
- Come join us. - So sorry.
-我都睡了  -这样啊...
- I was asleep. - Oh. We'll...
-我们去书房  -谢谢
- We'll move into the study. - Thank you.
弗兰西斯
Francis?
我就去
I'll be right there in a minute.
我不喜欢让他来这里
I don't like him being up here.
我们会小点声的
We'll be more quiet.
这是我们私人的空间
This is our private space.
-他是我的客人  -他是个陌生人
- He's my guest. - He's a stranger.
好吧  今晚之后  再不请他来了
All right. After tonight, no more.
我不是不讲理
I'm not being unreasonable.
我该...
I should've...
意识到我们是多吵
realized how much noise we were making.
能问你个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
你不就是来问问题的吗
Well, that's what you're here for, isn't it?
你们怎么不睡一个屋
Why don't you sleep in the same room?
我们搬过来
Uh, that just sorta happened over...
几个月后  就开始了
a few months after we moved in here.
一切都还好吗
Everything okay?
你俩之间
Between you two?
当然
Oh, you bet.
虽然不算最好的时候
Well, it's been better.
不  不太好
No, it's not okay.
你俩从莫斯科回程时的争执
The fight. Coming back from Moscow.
你听到了
You heard us?
只听到吵嚷声  听不清话
The yelling. Not what you said.
我们不怎么吵架
We don't fight often, but, uh...
但这一次
This one...
总是揭旧伤疤
scabs keep coming off.
我们说了些过分的话
We said things.
无法收回的话
Things you just can't take back.
很晚了  我们到此为止吧
It's late. We should call it a night.
托马斯
Thomas.
我对低俗内容没兴趣
I have no interest in salaciousness.
8月14日是罗斯福新政的纪念日
August fourteenth is the anniversary of the New Deal.
届时要达到两万
I'd like to hit 20,000 by that date.
应该没问题  先生
I believe we can do that, sir.
雷米  参议院用来挑战
Remy, what's the timeline
联邦应急管理署拨款合法性的修正案的进度如何
on the Senate bill outlawing FEMA funds?
立法办公室预测参议院法案
The Leg office predicts the Senate version
将在两三周内通过
will pass in two to three weeks.
我们在跟国会内的盟友想办法
Working with friendlies in the House.
搞点破坏  拖慢进度
Throw some pork on it, slow it down.
所以我们更该加速进展了
That's all the more reason that we need to accelerate.
如果我要否决这项法案
If I'm gonna veto this bill,
一定要拿阻碍五万人就业为理由
I want it to be because it's gonna kill 50,000 new jobs.
-我们创造的就业机会  -是  先生
- Jobs that we created. - Yes, sir.
凯茜
Cathy?
俄罗斯在约旦河谷问题上仍不肯妥协
The Russians remain intransigent on the Jordan Valley.
大使在努力
The ambassador is working hard
推动联合国大会就
to push the peacekeeping resolution to a vote
-维和决议案投票  -为什么延迟了
- by the General Assembly. - Why the delay?
我们无法说服非洲集团
We're having a hard time getting the African bloc
去掉坏事的条款
to remove the poison pill provision.
我们认为是以色列搞的鬼  他们临阵怯场
We think Israel's behind it. They got cold feet,
便让非洲集团
convinced the African bloc
破坏决议案进程  他们好下台
to sabotage the resolution so they have an out.
要我去跟总理谈谈吗
Do I need to speak to the Prime Minister?
以色列大使已经否认了
Uh, the Israeli ambassador has already denied.
我觉得我们该专注于条款本身
I think we need to keep our focus on the provision itself.
好吧
All right.
非洲集团的首领是津巴布韦
The head of the African bloc is Zimbabwe.
我们认为以色列保证
And we believe Israel has promised
给他们一个价值可观的艾滋防治援助项目
them a sizable aid package for HIV prevention.
国务卿和我建议
The Secretary and I recommend
提高我们给津巴布韦的救济金
increasing our relief funds to Zimbabwe.
超过以色列人
Outspend the Israelis.
金培图总统只会把钱中饱私囊
Well, President Chimbetu will just pocket the money.
我们早预计会遇到一定程度的腐败
Well, we always anticipate a certain level of graft.
一定程度  他是个贪婪透顶的恶魔
A certain level? He's egregious. The man's a monster.
可他是非洲集团的首领
Who happens to run the African bloc.
他是个要么屠杀人民  要么盗取他们财产的人
Who happens to kill his people when he's not stealing from them,
所以我才缩减了对津巴布韦的救济
which is why I reduced aid to Zimbabwe.
如果我们想让他撤销条款  我们就得有点筹码
If we want him to remove the amendment, we have to be persuasive.
我们已经在为《美就法》想方设法凑钱了
We are scraping together every penny we can to save AmWorks.
我最不需要的
The last thing I want
就是因为从国际开发署拨款给
is to be slammed for giving additional money
一个我想讨好的残忍独裁者
to a brutal dictator from USAID
而遭到抨击  这想法太糟了
just to persuade him. This is ill-conceived.
你提出这样的提议之前该三思
You should think before you bring a proposal such as this.
我们会考虑其他策略  再给您答复  总统先生
We'll pursue other strategies and get back to you, Mr. President.
谢谢  罗伯特  福利改革怎么样了
Thank you. Robert, what's the latest on the omnibus?
先生  法案再过
Sir, the legislation should go
两个月应该就能投票了
to the floor in the next couple of months.
领导层有反对...
The leadership is pushing...
联系洛克希德和诺斯罗普[均为军工企业]
Set up calls with both Lockheed and Northrop.
我们付钱让人接受培训  当做是工作
We'll pay people to get trained and call it a job.
是不是工作工会说了算
It isn't a job unless the union says it is.
一步步来嘛
Well, one step at a time.
你安排培训  我去找劳工联合会谈
You set up the training and I'll speak to the AFL.
退休者协会的人来了吗
Are the AARP here?
在大堂  主席说他们要支持邓巴
In the lobby. The chairman told me they want to support Dunbar.
他们只是想敲打我们
They're just trying to rattle us.
邓巴保证要挽救社会保险
Dunbar is promising to save Social Security.
从华尔街和政府浪费挤钱  而不是福利
Go after Wall Street and government waste instead of entitlements.
叫他们进来
Well, get them in here.
这是打电话名单
You have your call list.
他们的会面还有十分钟才开始
Their meeting's not for another ten minutes.
这就叫他们过来
Start bringing them over.
他们那么老  走过来也得十分钟了
It'll take them that long to hobble over on their walkers.
-弗兰西斯  -我去叫他们
- Francis? - I'll go get them.
我只有几分钟
I only have a few minutes.
你今天针对我是有意的
You singled me out today on purpose.
-什么  -内阁会议
- What? - The cabinet meeting.
如果我要让你参加内阁会议
If I'm gonna invite you to cabinet meetings,
就不能小心护着你
there's not gonna be any kid gloves.
别说得像照顾我
Don't make it sound like a favor.
你想去的  我同意了
You wanted to be there. I agreed.
为了获得信息  做好工作
Well, so I could be informed and do my job.
那房间里的每个人都靠工作能力受到审视
Everyone in that room is judged by what they bring to the table.
而你的工作不像样
What you brought to the table was amateurish.
凯茜和我一起提出了那个计划
Both Cathy and I proposed that plan.
我一样也怪她  你当我是在针对你
I fault her as much as you. You're making this too personal.
是针对我
It is personal.
我觉得你是在为俄罗斯的事惩罚我
I think you're punishing me for what happened in Russia.
得了
Oh, come on.
你在飞机上说  任命我是个错误
Well, you said it on the plane. Appointing me was a mistake.
你说的话更过分
Yeah, you said far worse things to me.
是啊  我也十分努力忘记那次的争吵
Yes, and I've gone out of my way to put that fight behind us.
是吗  像对托马斯那样
Oh, really? Like with Thomas?
我们把你吵醒  你就大吼大叫
When you screamed at us for waking you up.
-我才没大吼大叫  -你让我丢脸
- I didn't scream. - It was embarrassing.
谁管他怎么想呢
Who cares what he thinks?
他是我们的客人  你就那么走进来
He was our guest and you walked in there like--
我觉得你在无中生有
I think you're searching for things that aren't there
而对存在的问题又视而不见
and ignoring the things that are,
-比如拍照那档子事  -天呐
- like this photograph flinching nonsense.  - Oh, Jesus.
-你要我辞职吗  弗兰西斯  -别说傻话
- Do you want me to resign, Francis? - Don't be ridiculous.
说出来吧
Just say it.
你根本不希望我做大使
You never wanted me to be ambassador.
你记得你在飞机上对我说了什么吗
You remember what you said to me on the plane?
你不该让我当上总统
You should have never made me president.
我当时生着气  我不是那个意思
I was upset. I didn't mean it.
你就是那个意思  你觉得你造就了我
You did mean it. You think you made me.
不是的  我觉得我们是一个团队
No, I don't. I think we're a team, actually.
我们现在可不是
Well, we're not a team at the moment.
真难以置信我们变成了这样
I can't believe we've become this.
-什么样  -跟其他人一个样
- Become what? - Like everyone else.
可以了吗  先生
You ready, sir?
稍等一下  让烟味儿散去
No, just give me a minute. Let the smoke clear.
什么进度了
Where are we at?
她换发型了
Her hair's different.
但...
But I--
-这是在哪拍到的  -圣达菲
- Where was this taken? - Santa Fe.
我把搜索范围缩小到了那个城市
I've narrowed the search to focus just on that city.
我只有这么多  但我觉得这个开头不错
This is all I have, but I think it's a good start.
我该过去
I should go there.
不行  这是三周前的照片
No. These photos are three weeks old.
她可能只是路过那里
She might have been passing through.
也可能还留在那里
Or she might still be there.
好吧  但如果你去问东问西  可能会打草惊蛇
Okay, but if you start asking questions, you might tip her off.
那再找点信息来
Get me more, then.
我的护照怎么样了
How's my passport coming?
等你找到她  我就给你解锁
I'll get the lock lifted when you find her.
我给你看了我的进展
I've shown you some progress.
我也该看看你的进展
I think I should be seeing progress on your side, too.
这不够
This isn't enough.
他们又逮捕了我的一个朋友
They just arrested another one of my friends.
-他们随时能起诉我  -嘉文
- They could charge me at any minute. - Gavin...
我为了拿到这些  做了很糟糕的事
The things that I've had to do to get this much are fucked up.
准确地点
An exact location.
这是我们说好的
That was our deal.
你能把监控视频拿给我吗
Can you get me the camera feed?
系统有监控
The system's monitoring it.
我要
I want it, too.
我会把链接发给你
I'll send you the link.
道格  这是莫里斯
Doug? This is Maurice.
他会接手你  我要搬去西雅图了
He'll be taking over for me. I'm moving to Seattle.
我姐姐要自己开个锻炼中心
My sister's opening up her own PT center
她希望我去入伙
and she wants me to be a partner.
我要把所有客户都交给别人
I'm moving all my clients over to new folks.
这样我能帮助过渡
So I can help the transition.
真舍不得你走
I'll be sad to see you go.
我去拿几根漂浮杆
I'll go get some bar floats.
就回来
Back in a second.
我这周四要请人来做客
Look... I'm having people over this Thursday.
在我家开个欢送会  你也来吧
It's a going-away thing at my place. You should come.
-可以了吗  -嗯
- You ready? - Yeah.
具体情况发短信给你
I'll text you the details.
我要那些大人物的钱
I want to go after the big boys.
不仅是华尔街  还有沃尔玛
Not just Wall Street, but Walmart.
沃尔玛别轻易动
I'd be careful with Walmart.
你会在国会失去很多盟友
You'll lose a lot of friends in Congress.
那就逼他们选边站
Let's force them to take sides.
包括杰姬·夏普
That means Jackie Sharp, too.
推出法案
Introduce legislation.
她要么赞成  要么我们狠击她
She either votes for it or we hit her hard.
所有有超过10%员工
Any corporation who has more
在领食品救济券的大公司
than ten percent of its employees on food stamps
都要涨薪  直到这个数目低于10%
has to increase wages until they're below ten percent.
谁有胆支持这样的法案
Who has the guts to sponsor something like that?
道格
Doug?
嗯  我写份名单
Yeah, I'll put a list together.
你周末就能拿到
You'll have something by the end of the week.
好  到时再聊
Okay. Talk to you then.
你来了
You made it.
是啊
Yeah.
-来多久了  -10分钟
- How long have you been here? - Ten minutes.
来吧  我们得让大家舞起来
Come on. We need to get people dancing.
其实  我觉得我还是走吧
Actually, I was thinking that I should go.
我就是过来跟你道别的
I just came over to say goodbye.
不行  你哪都别想去
No. You are not going anywhere.
你不非得跳舞  但你也别想跑
You don't have to dance, but you can't leave.
就剩你还没醉倒
Last man standing.
你回收吗
You have recycling?
放在桌台上就好
Just leave 'em on the counter.
我明天收拾
I'll take care of it tomorrow.
你不用帮忙的
You really don't have to help.
我不介意
I don't mind.
你真绅士
You're such a gentleman.
这你不能确定
I don't know about that.
你不是绅士吗
Oh, you're not a gentleman?
那就...有意思了
Because... that could be interesting.
我给你泡了牛奶咖啡
I made you a café au lait.
怎么样
How is it?
-还要加糖吗  -不用
- Need sugar? - No.
很棒
It's perfect.
你的搬家工什么时候来
When are the movers coming by?
还有两小时呢
Not for a couple hours.
要我帮忙打包剩下的东西吗
You need any help? Packing the rest up?
不用  你休息吧
No. You just relax.
你昨晚似乎有点难过
You seemed a little sad last night.
没有  就是累了
No, just tired.
是吗  只是累了吗
Was that it? You were just tired?
有个我很久没联络的人
Someone I haven't heard from in a long time.
她联系我了
She reached out. It was--
我有点难过
It was a little hard.
你昨晚不是因为可怜我吧
Last night wasn't 'cause you felt sorry for me, was it?
不是
No.
昨晚是因为我今天要坐飞机走了
Last night was because I'm getting on a plane today,
我可能再也见不到你了
and I'll probably never see you again.
何乐不为呢
Why not?
西雅图经常下雨  你知道吧
You know it rains a lot in Seattle, right?
你今天跟我去纪念馆吗
Are you gonna come with me to the memorial today?
我一定要去吗
Do I need to be there?
不
No.
我现在忙死了
I'm buried right now.
好吧
Fine.
汤姆·耶茨最近怎么总在这儿晃
Why has Tom Yates been hanging around so much?
他要给总统写书吗
Is he writing a book on the president?
我们都问过  他不肯说
We've all asked him and he won't say.
如果真是可很大胆
Ballsy move if it's true.
嗯  我受不了他的文笔
Yeah. I can't stand his writing.
你傻逼吗
Are you an idiot?
有看法就傻逼了
I'm an idiot for having an opinion?
有什么可"看法"的  他文笔多棒
There's no opinions to be had. His writing is gorgeous.
我的看法就是  我不觉得
Well, in my opinion, it isn't.
自己购物单都写不好还说别人
Said the guy who can't write a grocery list.
就等您了  先生
Ready whenever you are, sir.
今天是《社会保险法案》的80周年纪念日
Today marks the 80th Anniversary of the Social Security Act.
它的存在时间  甚至超过了不少其受益人
It has survived longer than many of its beneficiaries.
希望所有人都能活到它这个岁数
We should all be so lucky to live as long as it has.
但当人活到80
But by the time the human body has circled the sun 80 times,
青春和活力就已不再
its youth and vigor are gone.
关节疼  骨头变脆  肌肉退化
Joints ache, bones and muscles are weaker,
心脏的跳动也不如从前强健了
the heart doesn't beat with the same power it once did.
我们所有人都最终得面对这一事实
All of us must face this truth eventually.
到那时  我们就得把接力棒交给下一代
And when we do, we must hand the baton to the young.
那些等我们离世后
To those who have the strength
有力量继续我们事业的人
to carry on our work when we are gone.
这一点也是事实  社会保险在崩溃
Here's another truth: Social Security is dying.
如今  值其80岁之际  它必须向
Now in its 80th year, it must give way
一个更年轻  更有力的新未来计划让位
to a new, younger, stronger plan for the future.
这就是《美国就业法案》
That plan is America Works.
光是在华盛顿特区  我们就将失业率
In Washington DC alone, we've managed to reduce unemployment
削减了超过三分之一  2.5万人找到了工作
by over a third and put 25,000 people to work.
如果我们能在这么短的时间里
If we can accomplish so much
在华盛顿做出这么大的成就
in so little time here in Washington,
想象一下如果国会在全国范围内
imagine what we could accomplish
为《美国就业法案》提供资金
if Congress funded America Works
又将取得多大成就
nationwide.
那就不是几万份工作了
We wouldn't be talking about thousands of jobs.
而是数百万
We'd be talking about millions.
今天下午晚些时候
Later this afternoon,
我会前往罗斯福纪念馆  向那个80年前
I will visit FDR's memorial to pay my respects to the man
推行了《社会保险法案》的人致敬
who ushered in Social Security 80 years ago.
我们致敬先人留给我们如今的世界
We honor the dead for giving us the world we inherited.
但我们也得认识到
However, we must recognize
如果让先人管束我们  就只有死路一条
we are doomed if we allow the dead to govern us.
谢谢  天佑美利坚合众国
Thank you, and God bless the United States of America.
华盛顿NBC新闻
From NBC News in Washington,
这里是《恰克·托德新闻访谈》
this is Meet the Press with Chuck Todd.
早上好  欢迎收看《新闻访谈》
Good morning and welcome to Meet the Press.
我身边是亨特利和格里尔议员
I have with me Congresswoman Huntley and Congressman Greer.
议员女士  我先问您吧
Congresswoman, let me start with you.
总统今日在无线电讲话中
In the President's radio address today,
称华盛顿的案例是全国的榜样
he said the model here in Washington is a model for the nation.
您赞同吗
Do you agree?
是的  恰克
I do, Chuck.
我起初持怀疑态度
I was skeptical at first.
马萨诸塞州民主党众议员丽贝卡·亨特利
我父母都是社会保险的受益人
Both my parents benefited from Social Security.
我自己也一直指望它
And I've always counted on it for myself.
但当我想到我的孩子  孙辈
But, when I think about my kids, and my grandkids--
丽贝卡提出了一个好观点  几十年来
Rebecca raises a good point, one that we've been making
我们在共和党内一直在提出这个问题
in the Republican Party for decades.
但是  您虽然支持《美国就业法案》
And yet, while you support America Works,
贵党党内大多持反对态度
most members of your party do not.
恰克  我向来不怎么喜欢弗兰克·安德伍德
Chuck, I've never been a big fan of Frank Underwood.
但我华盛顿的家附近的公园从未像如今这么干净
But the park near my house here in Washington has never been cleaner.
我光顾的干洗店本月雇了两名新员工
The dry cleaners I go to just hired two new people this month.
阿拉巴马州共和党众议员卡尔森·格里尔
我送孩子去的日托所的员工翻了倍
The daycare I drop my kids off at doubled their staff
这样每个孩子受到的个性化关注更多了
so the children can get more individual attention.
总统拿联邦应急管理署的钱或许是过分了
The president may have overstepped in taking FEMA money,
但成功就是成功  《美国就业法案》成功了
but when something works, it works. And America Works works.
进步的证明不是让富人更富有  而是令穷人不困苦
他们有意建立个别人统治全人类的政府系统
还称之为新秩序  这早有先例  而且不算"秩序"
原话是指纳粹
你好
Hello.
埃莉诺·罗斯福  美国首位驻联合国大使
给他们钱
Promise the money.
用一切手段让他回心转意
Whatever you need to turn him around.
我会批准从国际开发署拨款
I'll approve the USAID funds.
你为什么改主意了
What made you change your mind?
今天  在纪念馆
Today... at the memorial.
你知道最触动我的是什么吗
You know what struck me the most?
埃莉诺
Eleanor.
她一个人在旁边
She was off by herself.
孤身一人
Alone.
富兰克林也是  一个人
And so was Franklin. He was alone.
他们之间隔着墙
And there was a wall between them.
那些僧人
The monks.
他们来几周了  我们从没谈起过他们
They've been here for weeks. We haven't even discussed them once.
很美妙吧  他们的作品
It's beautiful, isn't it? What they're doing?
是啊
It is.
弗兰西斯  我今天看他们看了一个多小时
Francis, I watched them for over an hour today.
我一直在想着
And all I was thinking was,
我们为什么没有一起分享此刻
why aren't you and I sharing this together?
我们得想想办法  克莱尔
We have to do something, Claire.
我知道
I know.
你想怎么弄
What are you thinking?
我本来的发色  像我初识弗兰西斯时那样
My natural color. Like when I first met Francis.
-这个吗  -对
- This color? - Yes. Exactly.
好  请坐
Okay. Have a seat.
我想再修修袖子
I want to take up the sleeves a touch.
我觉得很好了  谢谢
Oh, I think they're perfect. Thank you.
-怎么样  -真美
- What do you think? - Beautiful.
我们今天聚集于此
We have gathered today
重证弗兰西斯·J·安德伍德
to renew the vows between Francis J. Underwood
和克莱尔·黑尔·安德伍德的婚誓
and Claire Hale Underwood.
就在这座教堂
It was here, in this church,
28年前  在上帝面前
28 years ago, before God,
你们二人首次向对方许下了誓言
that you two first committed yourselves to one another.
愿这再次确认的承诺  能加深你们的爱情
May this renewed commitment deepen your love for each other,
让你们的婚姻更加坚固  直到永远
and strengthen your eternal bond.
克莱尔的父亲给我们买下了这栋房子
Claire's father bought us this house.
我本想自己出钱  这事一直让我介意
I wanted to pay for it myself. That's always bothered me.
你不介意他为你首次竞选出资吗
You weren't bothered to let him pay for your first campaign?
那是政治  不一样
Well, that's politics. It's different.
筹钱要上天入地
You take money wherever you can get it.
这是我们第一个家
No, this was our first home.
-是个快乐的家吗  -拜托
- Was it a happy home? - Oh, please.
我以为你带我来
I thought you brought me here
就是想不再扯谎了
because we were gonna cut through the bullshit.
这本书要写的是《美国就业法案》
This book is supposed to be about America Works.
你必须作为书的核心  否则无法成书
There is no book without you at the center of it.
你信任我吗  还是不信任
Do you trust me? Or don't you?
你如果不信任我  就另找人写吧
Because if you don't, get someone else to write it.
或者你自己写
Or write it yourself.
你不知道过日子
You don't know what it's like
还得随时小心翼翼是什么滋味
to go through life looking over your shoulder.
背负没人能理解的秘密
Having secrets no one would understand.
我第一本书不是自己写的
I didn't write my first book.
我的朋友
My friend.
死掉的那个
The one who died.
是他写的
He wrote it?
前半部分  只给我一人看了
The first half. He didn't show it to anyone except me.
在医院时  他求我销毁书稿
In the hospital, he asked me destroy it.
我告诉他我会的
I told him I would.
但他写得太好
It was too good.
该写完  我就给写完了
It needed to be finished. So I finished it.
并说是你独立创作
And took all the credit.
是啊  是我写的结局
Oh, yeah. It's my part, the ending.
才是人们记住的部分
That's what people remember.
但那本书
But the book...
我整个职业生涯
My entire career...
都是基于一个谎言
It's all based on a lie.
秘密不是你一个人的专属
You don't have a monopoly on secrets.
这里地下埋了郁金香
There's tulips buried under here.
克莱尔种的
Claire planted them.
我一直
I've always...
从最开始
from day one...
就对她答应我的求婚感到羞耻
been ashamed she said yes when I asked her to marry me.
为什么
Why?
我觉得我配不上她
I didn't think I deserved her.
但我告诉你
I can tell you this, though,
如果不是克莱尔  我就不能入主白宫
there would have been no White House without Claire.
遇见她成就了更好的我
I was half the man before I met her.
但是  我很自私
But still, I've been selfish...
那样向她索取
feeding off her the way I have.
她清楚自己选择了什么
She knew what she was getting into.
或许吧  她比我更了解我
Probably. She knows me better than I know myself.
先生  我们计划是6点15分起航
Sir? We're scheduled to fly out at 6:15.
再过几分钟就得动身了
Should probably leave in the next few minutes.
谢谢  密查姆
Thank you, Meechum.
写吧
Scribble away.
他在房子前跟你说什么了
So, what'd he tell you in front of the house?
没什么
Nothing much.
不管是什么  似乎挺动情
Well, it looked intense, whatever it was.
瞧  这就是我不做大车的原因
See? This is why I don't ride in the van.
这次不是坐了
You did this time.
有时候得让人静静
Sometimes you just need to leave someone alone.
好吧  我懂了
All right, I got the hint.
我是说他  不是我自己
I meant him. Not me.
他们哪去了
Where are they?
-谁  -那些僧人
- Who? - The monks.
他们今天早些时候做完了  先生
Oh, they finished earlier today, sir.
没了吗
So it's gone?
是的
I believe so.
我都没来得及看到
I didn't get a chance to see it.
他们应该拍过照
I'm sure they took a photo.
你能叫人给我弄一份吗
Will you ask someone to get me a copy?
这就去  先生
Right away, sir.
克莱尔  我差点没认出来
Claire. I almost didn't recognize you.
是啊  我决定该做点改变了
Yes, I decided it was time for a change.
很迷人啊
It's very fetching.
希望您不介意我不请自来
I hope you don't mind me crashing your party.
当然不  我的手下说你不在市里
Oh, of course not. My staff said you'd be out of town.
介意我跟卡斯皮大使单独谈谈吗
Would you mind if I borrowed Ambassador Caspi for a moment?
请吧
Of course.
你躲了我三周
You've been avoiding me for three weeks.
我去了耶路撒冷
I had a trip to Jerusalem.
你答应给津巴布韦三千五百万
You promised Zimbabwe 35 million
让他们提出会坏事的无理条款
so they'd introduce the poison pill amendment.
-只是出于人道主义考虑  -不是的
- For purely humanitarian reasons. - No.
这是你们第一次给津巴布韦援助
This is the first time you've ever sent aid to Zimbabwe.
别乱牵线
Don't draw connections that don't exist.
我们绝不会给决议案搞破坏
We would never try to sabotage the resolution.
美国是我们的盟友
The United States is our ally.
是啊  我们是
That's right, we are.
那就有点盟友的样子
So act like it.
什么
Excuse me?
我丈夫已经正式批准
My husband formally approved
向津巴布韦提供八千万人道主义援助金
our own humanitarian package for eighty million.
他们明天就将撤回条款
Zimbabwe will be withdrawing the amendment tomorrow.
决议案进入投票时
And when the resolution goes to a vote,
希望以色列像个忠诚的盟友那样表示支持
I expect Israel to support it like the loyal ally she is.
而不是背信弃义
Not lie to us.
这可不是博取我们支持的方式
That's not the way to solicit our support.
我没想"博取"  我在要求
I'm not soliciting. I'm demanding.
我可怜你  克莱尔
I feel sorry for you, Claire.
你丈夫要你来说狠话
Your husband sends you to talk tough.
但等约旦河谷出了岔子
But as soon as things go wrong in the Jordan Valley,
他就会甩手不管  让以色列收拾烂摊子
he'll turn his back and leave Israel to clean up the mess.
他根本没这个实力
He doesn't have the muscle.
他没法让国会配合他
He can't even get Congress to work with him.
你羞辱佩特罗夫后都不能支持你
Or back you up after you call out Petrov.
他背叛了你  也会如此对我们
He turned his back on you just like he will on us.
我丈夫是我见过的最勇敢  最有决心的人
My husband is the bravest and most resolute man I know.
他的计划会成功的
He will succeed in this plan.
勇敢
Brave?
我在约旦河谷服过役
I served in Jordan Valley.
我国总统和外交部长也是  他呢
As did the President and the Foreign Minister. Has he?
你不过是举着枪  听命令
You held a gun and somebody told you where to stand.
别把这跟三军统帅的重担搞混
Don't confuse that with the burden the Commander in Chief faces.
弗兰西斯曾下令杀人
Francis has given the order to kill.
他曾下葬过他送入虎口的士兵
He's buried soldiers he's put into harm's way.
每一天  他承受的责任
And every day, he wakes up bearing responsibilities
都是你无法想象的
you can't possibly imagine.
如果你来承担  你会崩溃的
They would crush you if they fell on your shoulders.
你去告诉你的上级
So you talk to your superiors.
等明天条款撤销
And when the amendment is withdrawn tomorrow,
你必须支决议案
you will commit to supporting the resolution.
吾爱
没什么是永久的
除了我们
富兰克林·罗斯福婚后的大部分时间  都有自己的秘密情人
同夫人埃莉诺相守时间很少
有历史学者认为  埃莉诺之所以为人权和妇女权益不停奔波呼吁
很大程度上也是因为需要有自己的事业来缓解感情上的创痛
克林顿在任期间  同实习生的性丑闻搞得天下皆知
但是第一夫人希拉里仍然决定维持这段婚姻
离开白宫后  希拉里竞选议员  竞选总统  担任国务卿
而比尔·克林顿则到世界各地为自己的慈善基金会奔忙  两人聚少离多
2008年希拉里竞选总统时
华盛顿有传闻称克林顿多年在外面有自己的情人
有些民主党议员担心克林顿的新丑闻被媒体揭发后
会不利于希拉里的竞选  不过后来媒体并没有爆什么料
希拉里也一直把克林顿当作自己的政治顾问
外界认为  两人之间更多的是政治盟友的关系